SIERRAMATICE KARRAS

cckarras@gmail.com | 206-669-1122 https://www.linkedin.com/in/sierramatice-karras/ Seattle, WA

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Experienced Clinical Informatics Specialist with a strong background in designing and developing user-centered web interfaces for clinical and public health applications including prostate cancer, dementia, HIV and mental health. Proficient in facilitating communication between developers and medical professionals to ensure accurate implementation of clinical requirements, conducting usability studies, and performing quality assurance testing. Committed to creating intuitive and effective digital solutions that enhance user engagement and support research objectives.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Human Centered Design & Engineering | University of Washington Minor in Urban Ecological Design *Dean's List*

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Washington School of Nursing

1959 NE Pacific Street, Seattle, WA 98195

UI/UX Designer & Researcher/Web Computing Specialist

09/16/2016 - Present

- Member of the UW Clinical Informatics Research Group (CIRG).
- Contributed to the design, prototyping, and development of web-based interfaces focused on clinical and public health applications for education, data collection and research dissemination on a wide variety of subjects including prostate cancer, dementia, HIV and mental health.
- Designed, prototyped, and developed web layouts, navigation systems, custom icons, logos, and cohesive brand identities to enhance user engagement and visual consistency.
- Conducting heuristic and interview-based usability studies to identify user pain points and improve system usability.
- Applied scenario-based design methods to develop and test workflows for clinical care and public health systems.
- Performed QA testing across multiple platforms to ensure functionality and user experience consistency in clinical care and research systems.
- Facilitated communication and translation between software developers and medical professionals to ensure accurate implementation of clinical requirements.
- Conducted accessibility testing to ensure compliance with WCAG standards and improve usability for all users, including those with disabilities.

- Led rapid iteration cycles, incorporating user feedback into continuous UI/UX improvements and design refinements.
- Acted as a liaison between backend developers and stakeholders to ensure technical solutions aligned with user needs and workflows. Notable organizations include: the CDC, Washington State Department of Health, Movember, USAA Face the Fight Foundation and a wide number of Universities and Hospitals around the country.
- *Key Skills:* Usability Research, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Wireframing, Interaction Design, Web & Mobile App Design, Scenario-Based Testing, Heuristic Evaluation, Epic.

CoMotion Mobility Innovation Center, King County Metro/Sound Transit 1959 NE Pacific Street, Seattle, WA 98195

Lead Designer & Prototyper/Co-Lead of Research & Evaluation

01/2019 - 10/2019

- HCDE Senior Capstone Project—People's Choice Award Winner
- Conducted in-depth interviews with a diverse group of public transit riders to understand usage patterns, pain points, and interest in a mobile alternative to physical ORCA cards.
- Designed and built an interactive mobile app prototype that included core features as digital payment, streamlined features, account management, and customization/personalization
- Coordinated directly with project sponsors, leading regular communication, planning, and cross-functional collaboration.
- Researched and conducted a comparative UX analysis of fare systems in Boston,
 Sydney AUS, and Pierce County to identify best practices and design opportunities for the ORCA app prototype.
- Delivered a user-centered design proposal to representatives from King County Metro and Sound Transit, highlighting usability findings, mapping, and mockups
- Led project management efforts, ensuring timely delivery and cohesive team execution throughout the design process.
- King County Metro and Sound Transit quickly integrated ideas of adding local sports team branding into ORCA card designs to enhance community engagement and visual appeal.
- Prototype influenced the direction of King County Metro and Sound Transit's final mobile product.
- *Key Skills:* Visual Design, Interaction Design, Prototyping, User Research, Usability Research.

Freelance Design Consultant | Self-Employed Present

01/2015 -

 Designed custom products and logos tailored to clients' specific needs, enhancing brand identity and user engagement.

- Developed prototypes using 3D modeling, laser cutting, and paper prototyping techniques to visualize and test design concepts.
- Employed a diverse range of design software to select the most appropriate tools for each project's requirements.
- Managed end-to-end project lifecycles, including client communication, scope definition, timeline management, and resource allocation, ensuring timely and successful project delivery.
- *Key Skills:* Creative Design, Interaction Design, Prototyping, Product Design, Communication, Project Management.

PUBLICATIONS

- <u>Let's Talk Tech: Supporting family decisions about dementia home care</u> <u>technologies - University of Washington Memory and Brain Wellness Center.</u> September 2022.
- Advance Planning for Technology Use in Dementia Care: Development, Design, and Feasibility of a Novel Self-administered Decision-Making Tool. Clara Berridge; Natalie R Turner; Liu; Sierramatice W Karras; Amy Chen; Karen Fredriksen-Goldsen; and George Demiris. *JMIR Publications*, 5(3). May 2022.
- A toolkit to support the implementation of patient reported outcome measures in routine HIV care [Poster]. Duncan Short; Heidi M. Crane; Justin McReynolods; Sierramatice Karras; and Rob J Fredericksen. *Oral presentation: ISOQOL 28th Annual Conference*. October 2021.
- StayHome: A FHIR-Native Mobile COVID-19 Symptom Tracker and Public Health Reporting Tool. Hannah Burkhardt; Pascal Brandt; Jenney Lee; Sierramatice Karras; Paul Bugni; Ivan Cvitkovic; Amy Chen; and William Lober. Online Journal of Public Health Informatics, 13(1). March 2021. Number: 1
- PROgress Implementation Toolkit: Integrating Patient-Reported Outcomes

 (PROs) Assessments Into Routine HIV Care. Rob J Fredericksen; Duncan Short;

 Emma Fitzsimmons; Justin McReynolods; Sierramatice Karras; William Lober; and Heidi Crane. Funded by ViiV Healthcare as part of the PROgress Study. November 2020.
- **2019 HCDE Open House People's Choice Award.** Human Centered Design; and Engineering University Washington. June 2019.

VOLUNTEER & LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE The Fremont Abbey

Volunteer Event Coordinator

09/2024 - Present

- Oversee day-of event operations to ensure seamless execution and adherence to event schedule.
- Manage ticketing and admissions, providing attendees with timely assistance and information.

- Coordination of setting up for events, ensuring all equipment and materials were in place and functioning properly.
- Served as a primary point of contact for musical artists, ensuring they had all necessary accommodation and support for the event.
- Key Skills: Project Management, Strategic Thinking, Communication

Human Centered Design and Engineering Industry Mentor for HCDE Student Groups

02/2021 - 08/2023

- Provided mentorship to undergraduate and graduate students in the HCDE program, offering guidance on user-centered design practices, career development, and industry trends.
- Supported student teams through project planning, iteration, and presentation processes, promoting collaborative problem-solving and inclusive design.
- Acted as a bridge between academia and industry, sharing real-world insights to enhance student learning and readiness for professional roles.
- Key Skills: Communication, Mentorship

UW Campus Sustainability Fund

Vice-Chair & Voting Committee Member

09/2015 - 08/2017

- Reviewed and coached sustainability projects applying for funding.
- Assisted in management and budgeting of over \$300,000 a year.
- Collaborated on interviewing and hiring new committee members.
- Key Skills: Project Management, Leadership, Strategic Thinking

Roosevelt High School Engineering Lab

2014 - 2015

Lead of Interdisciplinary Engineering, Design and Build Shop

- President and founder of the school's Technology Student Association (TSA) chapter
- Member of Iron Riders FIRST Robotics Team
- Planned, organized and managed projects, including budgeting, assigning tasks and status meetings.
- Managed and operated shop and lab equipment including: 3D printers, laser cutters, and a wide variety of other prototyping tools
- Key Skills: Project Management, Leadership, Strategic Thinking, Communication

Center for American Indian and Indigenous Studies at University of Washington 2014 Native Youth Enrichment Program

- Collaborated with fellow volunteers to organize activities and run logistics for the youth participants.
- Key Skills: Project Management, Communication, Mentorship

REFERENCES

William Lober, Professor & Principal Investigator | lober@uw.edu
Justin McReynolds, Technical Program Manager | mcjustin@uw.edu
Kameil Borders, SoN HR & Payroll Services Director | kborders@uw.edu
Nataile Chow, UX Designer | natalie.michelle.chow@gmail.com
Anna Evanson, Research Scientist & Project Manager | annaee@uw.edu
Jill Aneri Shah, User Experience Researcher & Lecturer | jillanerishah@gmail.com